# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hello, everyone. I am Wang Gang
# 本期视频我跟大家分享一道家常菜
In this video I m going to share an ordinary home cook meal with you.
# 懒人烧豆腐
Lazy Man’s Fried Tofu.
# 首先我们准备老豆腐2大块（约500克）
Firstly, we prepare 2 pieces of firm tofu. (around 500 g)
# 将老豆腐切成厚片备用（约0.8厘米）
cut the tofu into thick slices. (0.8 cm width)
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Next, prepare the minor ingredients.
# 准备小米辣几个切碎备用
Prepare "Xiaomila" chili pepper, mince.
# 准备二荆条2个从中间片开之后切碎备用
Prepare 2 piece of "Erjingtiao" chili pepper. Cut from the middle and then mince.
# 准备大蒜2颗拍散之后剁碎备用
Prepare 2 pieces of garlic. Crush them and then mince.
# 准备韭菜几根切成小段备用
Prepare a few Chinese chives. Cut into small pieces.
# 喜欢吃肉的同学可以加一些五花肉
For those meat lovers, you can put in some pork belly.
# 下一步开始准备料汁
Next, prepare the sauce.
# 碗中加入食用盐半勺（约1克）
Put half a spoonful of salt into the bowl. (around 1 g)
# 加入少许白糖
Add a little bit of sugar.
# 加入生抽酱油6克
Add 6 g of soy sauce.
# 加入蚝油3克
Add 3 g of oyster sauce.
# 加入清水150克
Add 150 g of plain water.
# 最后加入1大勺土豆淀粉搅拌均匀备用
At last, add one cooking spoon of potato starch. Stir until even.
# 下一步开始制作
Next, we start to cook.
# 首先我们把锅烧热
Firstly, let’s heat up the wok.
# 锅烧热之后加入适量的植物油
When the wok is heated, put in some vegetable oil to grease the wok.
# 滑好锅之后将热油倒出之后再加入少许的底油
After that, get rid of the greasing oil. Then put in some base oil.
# 在锅中撒入少许的食用盐
Add a little bit of salt.
# 然后将切好的老豆腐依次下入锅中
Then we put in our sliced tofu into the wok piece by piece.
# 同学们加盐煎豆腐可以防止粘锅
Note that salt prevents tofu from sticking onto the wok during frying.
# 同时还能够去除豆腥味
And meantime, the unwanted odor of tofu can be removed.
# 豆腐下锅之后再加入适量的油从锅边淋入
After putting tofu into the wok, add some more oil from the edges of the wok.
# 然后转中小火煎6分钟
Turn down the heat to medium-low. Then fry for 6 mins.
# 煎的过程中必须随时摇动豆腐防止煎糊
During frying, keep moving tofu pieces in wok to prevent overcooking.
# 中途再翻过来煎另一面
At halfway, flip the tofu and fry the other side.
# 将豆腐煎至金黄色之后加入切好的辣椒和蒜末炒香
After the tofu turns into golden yellow, put peppers and garlic into the wok.
# 中途可以适当的加一些油来润锅
During cooking, you can put in some extra oil to keep the wok moist.
# 辣椒煎香之后将调好的料汁搅拌均匀下锅
After the aroma of the peppers comes out, add the sauce evenly into the wok.
# 汤汁稍浓之后加入切好的韭菜段烧至断生
After thickening the sauce, put in Chinese chives and soften them.
# 韭菜烧至断生之后即可出锅装盘
After Chinese chive are softened, the dish is ready to serve.
# 一道非常简单美味的烧豆腐就制作完成
And now a simple and delicious fried tofu is finished.
# 下面开始技术总结
# 第一，选择老豆腐煎出来比嫩豆腐更香且不容易碎
# 第二，煎豆腐的锅中不能有水否则容易粘锅煎碎
# 第三，此菜为懒人菜系全过程豆腐只需要翻一次即可
# 懒人烧豆腐的技术总结完毕
Technical summary.
Firstly, we use firm tofu instead of tender tofu, as it has a stronger flavor and doesn't break down easily.
Secondly, make sure there is no water in the wok during frying. Otherwise the tofu would stick onto the wok and easily break.
Thirdly, this dish fits lazy people. You only need to flip the tofu once during the whole cooking process.
That's all for Lazy Man’s Fried Tofu.